<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Contact Tracing</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Digital Contact Tracing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to our New Undergraduate Intern Andrew Solis</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/2021-02-11-welcome-to-our-new-undergraduate-intern-andrew-solis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/2021-02-11-welcome-to-our-new-undergraduate-intern-andrew-solis/</guid>
      <description>New undergraduate intern Andrew Solis has joined the project. Andrew is an undergraduate pursuing a degree in Geographic Information Science at Arizona State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January Update to Status of State DCTTs</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/2021-01-11-january-update-to-status-of-state-dctts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/2021-01-11-january-update-to-status-of-state-dctts/</guid>
      <description>Our most recent update update to the Status of State DCTTs Efforts in now available.
Since our previous update, we have seen the number of states who have either released or are planning to release a digital contract tracing (DCT) app increase from 7 to 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Print Examining the Connections and Tradeoffs of DCTT Published</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/2020-11-25-pre-print-examining-the-connections-and-tradeoffs-of-dctt-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/2020-11-25-pre-print-examining-the-connections-and-tradeoffs-of-dctt-published/</guid>
      <description>The pre-print of our forthcoming chapter Assessing Connections and Tradeoffs between Geosaptial Data Ethics, Privacy, and the Effectiveness of Digital Contact Tracing Technologies is available through the Location Tracking, Contact Tracing, and Geospatial Privacy During COVID-9 GitHub page.
In that pre-print Peter Kedron and Andrew Trgovac examines contact tracing, its potential extension using geospatial technologies, and the tradeoffs between privacy and effectiveness that may arise as these systems are developed and deployed to address COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September Update to Status of State DCTTs</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/september-update-to-status-of-state-dctts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/september-update-to-status-of-state-dctts/</guid>
      <description>Since our previous update, we have seen the number of states who have either released or are planning to release a digital contract tracing (DCT) app increase from 7 to 17. A common trend has been the increase in the number of Bluetooth-based apps.
Even states that had previously used GPS-based DCT apps (e.g. North Dakota and Wyoming) are switching to Bluetooth, citing privacy concerns. It was also recently announced that Apple and Google were going to streamline their digital tracking framework, making it easier for states to develop their own app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Summer Interns</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/2020-09-01-thank-you-summer-interns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/2020-09-01-thank-you-summer-interns/</guid>
      <description>Many, many thanks to our departing undergraduate summer interns - Roxane Avalos, Ricardo Charcas, Juan Mancillas, Daniel Spalla, Taylor The, and Brandon Wolff. Your diligence and persistence in tracking down information about DCTT around the country this summer were critical to the project. We wish you all the best and look forward to collaborating with all of you in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment Principles Published</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/assessment-principles-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/assessment-principles-published/</guid>
      <description>We have shared the Assessment Principles we are using to review DCTT Apps along with an Overview of our Data Collection Plan on the Project GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASU Researchers Investigate COVID-19 Impacts</title>
      <link>/press/asu-researchers-investigate-covid-19-impacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/press/asu-researchers-investigate-covid-19-impacts/</guid>
      <description>Three researchers at Arizona State University have been awarded research grants releated to COVID-19. You can read about the nature of their projects at the SGSUP ASU website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Website Launched</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/project-website-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/project-website-launched/</guid>
      <description>The website for the Location Tracking, Contact Tracing, and Geospatial Privacy of COVID-19 project is now live. The Project GitHub Repository is also available. We will soon be adding a range of project materials to that site.
Our work is funded by the U.S. National Science Foundation Award BCS-2032203. We hope the data and publications contained here will contribute to an informed public debate about the role DCTT can play during different phases of the pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Project</title>
      <link>/aboutproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutproject/</guid>
      <description>We are creating a database of the digital contact tracing technologies (DCTT) being used by public health authorities (PHA) in the United States to respond to the spread of SARS-COV-2, the virus responsible for COVID-19. While we collect data on many aspects of each individual DCTT, we are particularly interested in the geospatial technologies used in these systems, the location data they produce, and how that data is managed, stored, transferred, and shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Team</title>
      <link>/aboutteam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutteam/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Peter Kedron
Assistant Professor of Geography and Urban Planning at Arizona State University
Peter is a geographer and social scientist working at the intersection of spatial analysis, geographic information science (GIScience), and economic geography. His research program develops the methodological tools and analytical frameworks needed to uncover the causes of geographic phenomena, and, through the application of those innovations, he advances understandings of the interactions between humans and their natural and social environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>For more information regarding this project, please contact us at digitalcontacttracing@gmail.com.


You can also find us on social media and other places online:
Twitter 
GitHub 
OSF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Contact Tracing Technologies</title>
      <link>/technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/technologies/</guid>
      <description>A range of different technologies are now being developed, combined, and deployed to facilitate the tracing of contacts of individuals that have tested positive for COVID-19. These digital contact tracing technologies (DCTT) are a combination of the physical hardware embedded in device (e.g., the GNSS receiver on a mobile device), the software developed to use those devices (e.g., the API and accompanying application on a phone), and the operational protocols the govern these systems (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status of State Digital Contact Tracing Technologies</title>
      <link>/statestatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/statestatus/</guid>
      <description>Our project team is tracking how states are using digital contact tracing technologies (DCTT) to respond to COVID-19. The map and table below contain a summary of which states are using which technologies in their response. We will be regularly updating and expanding this information as the project progresses. More information about individual DCTT is available on our Technologies Page or through the Project GitHub Repository and the Project Open Science Framework Page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
