<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Contact Tracing</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Digital Contact Tracing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ASU Researchers Investigate COVID-19 Impacts</title>
      <link>/press/asu-researchers-investigate-covid-19-impacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/press/asu-researchers-investigate-covid-19-impacts/</guid>
      <description>Three researchers at Arizona State University have been awarded research grants releated to COVID-19. You can read about the nature of their projects at the SGSUP ASU website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Website Launched</title>
      <link>/projectupdates/project-website-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projectupdates/project-website-launched/</guid>
      <description>The website for the Location Tracking, Contact Tracing, and Geospatial Privacy of COVID-19 project is now live. The Project GitHub Repository is also available. We will soon be adding a range of project materials to that site.
Our work is funded by the U.S. National Science Foundation Award BCS-2032203. We hope the data and publications contained here will contribute to an informed public debate about the role DCTT can play during different phases of the pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Project</title>
      <link>/aboutproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutproject/</guid>
      <description>We are creating a database of the digital contact tracing technologies (DCTT) being used by public health authorities (PHA) in the United States to respond to the spread of SARS-COV-2, the virus responsible for COVID-19. While we collect data on many aspects of each individual DCTT, we are particularly interested in the geospatial technologies used in these systems, the location data they produce, and how that data is managed, stored, transferred, and shared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Team</title>
      <link>/aboutteam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutteam/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Peter Kedron
Assistant Professor of Geography and Urban Planning at Arizona State University
Peter is a geographer and social scientist working at the intersection of spatial analysis, geographic information science (GIScience), and economic geography. His research program develops the methodological tools and analytical frameworks needed to uncover the causes of geographic phenomena, and, through the application of those innovations, he advances understandings of the interactions between humans and their natural and social environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>For more information regarding this project, please contact us at digitalcontacttracing@gmail.com.


You can also find us on social media and other places online:
Twitter 
GitHub 
OSF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Contact Tracing Technologies</title>
      <link>/technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/technologies/</guid>
      <description>A range of different technologies are now being developed, combined, and deployed to facilitate the tracing of contacts of individuals that have tested positive for COVID-19. These digital contact tracing technologies (DCTT) are a combination of the physical hardware embedded in device (e.g., the GNSS receiver on a mobile device), the software developed to use those devices (e.g., the API and accompanying application on a phone), and the operational protocols the govern these systems (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status of State Digital Contact Tracing Technologies</title>
      <link>/statestatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/statestatus/</guid>
      <description>Our project team is tracking how states are using digital contact tracing technologies (DCTT) to respond to COVID-19. The map and table below contain a summary of which states are using which technologies in their response. We will be regularly updating and expanding this information as the project progresses. More information about individual DCTT is available on our Technologies Page or through the Project GitHub Repository and the Project Open Science Framework Page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>